(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we are gonna be teaching you
a very important technique,
especially for the guys,
if you wanna have good
luck with the ladies, right?
- Oh, Marco.
Well, today's lesson is
called, that's flattering.
- Right, so we are going to be
teaching you how to flatter someone.
- Okay, so what does it
mean to flatter someone?
- Well, basically you're going
to be giving compliments,
and you're gonna make that
person feel good about themselves.
- That's right.
- Okay, so flattering.
Now, before we get on
with this flattering lesson,
we need to look at some
vocabulary in vocabulary preview.
- Very vocabulary preview.
- All right, I'm vocabulary preview today.
We have two small words,
so the first one is bar exam.
- The bar exam.
- So the bar exam is that formal test
that lawyers must do to
become official lawyers.
- Right.
So it's that final exam in
order to finally become a lawyer.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, and what about our next word?
- Well, we're also gonna hear
in the dialogue, obnoxious.
- Obnoxious.
- Okay, so this is an adjective.
- Yes, and it means something
that is really, really annoying.
- Okay, so something can be obnoxious.
- Or someone? - Or someone.
Okay, very good.
So now we have these two words that
we're going to listen to in the dialogue.
And now let's listen to two people as
they flatter each other in our dialogue.
(upbeat music)
- Valerie.
- Hi, wow, how have you been?
It's been such a long time.
- Darlene, indeed, it's been a while.
How have you been?
How you look amazing.
I love what you've done with your hair.
- Really?
- Thanks.
I went to that hair
salon you told me about,
but enough about me.
- Look at you.
God, you haven't eaten today.
What is your secret?
- No.
- Come on.
Well, I've been watching what I eat,
and I work out three times a week.
By the way, I heard your
son recently graduated.
- Yes, my little paw is finally a doctor.
I grew up so fast, you know.
- He is such a handsome guy.
He gets his nooks from
his mother, of course.
- Thank you.
What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar
exam and married recently.
- Oh, yes, she had a beautiful wedding
in Cosamel, Mexico, and we all attended.
- Such a lovely girl.
- I hope my paw is lucky enough
to find a girl like that someday.
- But, of course.
Well, it's been great talking
to you, but I have to get going.
- Same here.
- We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
- That would be great.
Give me a cool.
- See you soon.
Bye.
(sighs)
I cannot stand that woman
or her obnoxious daughter.
- All right, so this is
your typical normal,
every day behavior that
women show to each other, right?
- Yeah, I think it's very common.
It's very hard to argue
against this because I think
everyone does it, or at least
you've heard maybe your mother,
or somebody talk to
her friends like this, right?
- So pretend you like a
person who you actually hate.
- Right, you have to be courteous.
- Is that what you're doing to me now?
- All right, no, I'm not, but we can take
a look at some of this great language,
very rich language that we found
in this dialogue, in Fluency Builder.
- Fluency Builder.
- All right, we're doing things a
little bit different in this lesson.
So we're going to do two Fluency Builders.
And in the first one,
we're going to focus
on language you can
use to flatter someone.
- Right, so let's get started.
In the very first part of the dialogue,
we heard Valerie say, "I love
what you've done with your hair.
" - I love what you've
done with your hair.
- I love what you've done with.
- Okay, so if somebody
says this, basically
they're saying, "I like
the change you made.
" - Okay, and change not
only to your hair, right?
- It could be anything.
So I love what you've
done with your new house.
- Okay, or I can say, "I love what
you've done with your garden.
It looks so beautiful.
" - So something that you've
changed, you can use this phrase for.
- Okay, and in this case, it's her hair.
So she is complimenting her on her hair.
- We also heard Darlene
say, "You haven't aged a day.
" - You haven't aged a day.
- You haven't aged a day.
- Okay, so now she is saying
that she hasn't gotten any older.
- That's right, two age is to get older.
- Okay, so this is a very common
way of telling somebody you look great.
- That's right, you look young.
- You look young, you look great.
You haven't aged a day.
- All right, so then they talk about their
kids and they're talking about the sign,
and Valerie says, "He's
such a handsome guy.
" - He is such a handsome guy.
- He is such a handsome guy.
- Okay, so this structure is
important because now I can
change the adjective, and I
am saying he is very intelligent.
He is such an intelligent guy.
- That's right, or even
this is such a good day.
- All right, very good.
So now why don't we combine
the two phrases that we've just heard.
I love what you've done with, and he is
such a, and let's listen to some examples.
- Example one, we love what
you've done with this place.
- It's such a beautiful room.
- Example two.
I love what you've done with
your hair, such a nice color on you.
Example three.
- I love what you've done with
this space, such a wonderful garden.
- Okay, I really like how those two phrases
can fit together.
- Yeah, they are very
good, and now you can use
them together or separately
like in the dialogue.
- That's right.
Now let's move to our
final flattering phrase.
Valerie says that Darlene Sun
gets his looks from his mother.
- Right, she says he gets his
looks from his mother, of course.
- He gets his looks from.
- Okay, so when she says he gets his
looks from, she's saying his appearance.
- His positive appearance,
his good appearance.
- Right, his good looks.
- Okay, so now we can change the noun,
and I can say he gets his
intelligence from his father.
- Right, or even he gets his beautiful
singing voice from his mother.
- Okay, so now typically
you would say his mother,
his father, or maybe one
of the grandparents, right?
- Maybe, yeah.
- But you wouldn't say he gets
his good looks from his brother.
- No, no, no, mother,
father, grandma, grandpa.
- All right, so now that
we've covered four great ways
of flattering someone, let's
listen to this dialogue again,
but we're gonna slow it down a little
bit so you can pick up on these phrases.
(upbeat music)
- Valerie, hi, wow, how have you been?
It's been such a long time.
- Darlene, indeed, it's been a while.
How have you been?
How you look amazing.
I love what you've done with your hair.
- Really?
- Thanks, I went to that
hair salon you told me about,
but enough about me.
Look at you, God, you
haven't eaten it today.
What is your secret?
- No, come on.
Well, I've been watching what I eat
and I work out three times a week.
By the way, I heard your
son recently graduated.
- Yes, my little Paul is finally a doctor.
They grew up so fast, you know.
- He is such a handsome guy.
He gets his looks from
his mother, of course.
- Thank you.
- What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar
exam and married recently.
- Oh, yes, she had a beautiful wedding
in Cosamel, Mexico, and we all attended.
- Such a lovely girl.
I hope my Paul is lucky enough
to find a girl like that someday.
- But it's of course.
Well, it's been great talking
to you, but I have to get going.
- Same here.
We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
- That would be great.
Give me a cool.
- See you soon, bye.
- Oh, I cannot stand that
woman or her obnoxious daughter.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so we see a lot of
great flattering language
in this dialogue, but we also
have some really good language
and phrases you can use
in small talk in any situation.
- Right, so maybe if you talk to a
friend that you haven't seen in a while,
we have some really great
phrases for, as you say, small talk.
- So let's look at those now
in fluency builder part two.
- Fluency builder.
- Okay, so let's start
with the first phrase.
She says, Valerie, hi, wow, how are you?
It's been such a long time.
- It's been such a long time.
So basically here she's saying we
haven't seen each other in a long time.
- Right, but it kind of gives you that idea
that she regrets not talking
her for such a long time.
- Yes, she wishes she
could have talked to her.
- It's been such a long time, how are you?
- So a wonderful way
to start a conversation.
So when they start
talking about their kids,
Valerie says, by the way, I heard
your son recently graduated.
- Right, by the way, I heard
- So this phrase, by
the way, I heard blah,
blah, blah, blah, is
really, really useful.
- Right, let's take a look
at the first part, by the way.
- So this is a way to connect to
different ideas or to start a new topic.
- Exactly.
And now when she says, I heard
your son recently graduated.
- So we use this phrase, I heard
when we've got information
that we're not sure about.
- Right, or also you are
demonstrating interest about a certain
topic or a news event that
you would like to know about.
- Right, and so basically you're asking
the other person, tell me about this.
- Right, so I can say, hey, by
the way, I heard you got married.
- So I'd then I'd tell you
all about my wedding.
- Exactly.
Okay, so this is a very common
way of talking to someone
or getting some more
information from a person.
So let's listen to some more
examples of, by the way.
Example one, by the way, I
heard you recently been promoted.
Example two, I heard your
daughter just had a baby.
Congratulations.
Example three, oh, I had you just
got back from holiday in France.
All right, now, since these
two ladies don't like each other
very much, they wanna
end the conversation, right?
- Right, they wanna end the conversation
and well, you wanna end
it in a polite way, right?
So they use a really great phrase here.
They said, it's been great talking
to you, but I have to get going.
- Right, so it's like, well, it's been great
talking to you, but I have to get going.
So it's been great talking to you.
I've enjoyed talking to you.
- Right, so this is a very
polite, very subtle way of
saying, hey, I have to go,
or bye, I can't talk anymore.
- Yeah, when you say that, you
know that the conversation is ending.
- Exactly.
Now, she says, I have to get going.
What does it mean, get going?
That doesn't make much sense.
- Basically, it just means leave.
- Okay, I have to leave.
I have to get going.
You should get going, you're gonna be late.
- Exactly.
- Some really good small talk
phrases that are useful in any situation.
So why don't we hear them again one
more time by listening to the dialogue.
- Valerie.
- Hi, wow, how have you been?
It's been such a long time.
- Darlene, indeed, it's been a while.
How have you been?
How you look amazing.
I love what you've done with your hair.
- Really?
- Thanks, I went to that
hair salon you told me about,
but enough about me.
- Look at you, God,
you haven't eaten today.
What is your secret?
No, come on.
Well, I've been watching what I eat
and I work out three times a week.
By the way, I heard your
son recently graduated.
- Yes, my little Paul is finally a doctor.
They grow up so fast, you know.
- He is such a handsome guy.
He gets his nooks and
his mother, of course.
- Thank you.
What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar
exam and married recently.
- Oh, yes, she had a beautiful wedding
in Cosamel, Mexico, and we all attended.
- Such a lovely girl.
- I hope my Paul is lucky enough
to find a girl like that someday.
- But it's of course.
- Well, it's been great talking
to you, but I have to get going.
- Same here.
We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
- That would be great.
Give me a cool.
- See you soon.
Bye.
- Ugh, I cannot stand that
woman or her obnoxious daughter.
- All right, very good.
So now you have a couple of phrases
that you can use to flatter someone,
be it your friend, or somebody
that you know, or anyone.
And well, they are very, very useful.
And if you use them correctly, of course.
- Right, and these phrases sound really
honest and really natural, very native-like.
- Okay, so if you have any
other questions or comments,
or if you want to share some other
phrases that you use to flatter people,
come to our website
at englishpod.
com and leave them in
our comments section.
- So Marco and I have to get going,
but we're looking forward
to seeing you on the website.
Thanks for listening.
And until next time.
Bye.
(upbeat music)